# Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one or more
# contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file distributed with
# this work for additional information regarding copyright ownership.
# The ASF licenses this file to You under the Apache License, Version 2.0
# (the "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance with
# the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at
#
#      http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
#
# Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
# distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
# WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
# See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
# limitations under the License.

# Please see the documentation for all configuration options:
# https://help.github.com/github/administering-a-repository/configuration-options-for-dependency-updates

version: 2
updates:
  - package-ecosystem: "maven"
    directory: "/"
    commit-message:
      prefix: "build"
      prefix-development: "build"
      include: "scope"
    schedule:
      interval: "daily"
    ignore:
      - dependency-name: "org.antlr:stringtemplate"
        versions:
          - ">= 4.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.apache.maven.plugins:maven-checkstyle-plugin"
        versions:
          - ">=3.1.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.apache.maven.plugins:maven-enforcer-plugin"
        versions:
          - ">= 3.0.0"
      # checkstyle 10 needs Java 11
      - dependency-name: "com.puppycrawl.tools:checkstyle"
        versions:
          - ">= 10.0"
      # todo: update quarkus
      - dependency-name: "io.quarkus:quarkus-maven-plugin"
        versions:
          - ">= 2.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.seleniumhq.selenium:selenium-java"
        versions:
          - ">= 4.0.0"
      # jakarta.el-api 5.0.0 is Jakarta EE 10
      - dependency-name: "jakarta.el:jakarta.el-api"
        versions:
          - ">= 5.0.0"
      # jakarta.enterprise.cdi-api 4.0.0 is Jakarta EE 10
      - dependency-name: "jakarta.enterprise:jakarta.enterprise.cdi-api"
        versions:
          - ">= 4.0.0"
      # jakarta.servlet.jsp.jstl-api 3.0.0 is Jakarta EE 10
      - dependency-name: "jakarta.servlet.jsp.jstl:jakarta.servlet.jsp.jstl-api"
        versions:
          - ">= 3.0.0"
      # jakarta.annotation-api 2.1 is Jakarta EE 10
      - dependency-name: "jakarta.annotation:jakarta.annotation-api"
        versions:
          - ">= 2.1.0"
      # jakarta.servlet:jakarta.servlet-api 6.x is Jakarta EE 10
      - dependency-name: "jakarta.servlet:jakarta.servlet-api"
        versions:
          - ">= 6.0.0"
      # weld 5 is CDI 4 is Jakarta EE 10
      - dependency-name: "org.jboss.weld.servlet:weld-servlet-shaded"
        versions:
          - ">= 5.0.0"
      # Jakarta Faces 4.0 is Jakarta EE 10
      - dependency-name: "org.glassfish:jakarta.faces"
        versions:
          - ">= 4.0.0"

  - package-ecosystem: "maven"
    directory: "/"
    target-branch: "tobago-5.x"
    commit-message:
      prefix: "build"
      prefix-development: "build"
      include: "scope"
    schedule:
      interval: "daily"
    ignore:
      # Jetty >= 10 requires jdk 11
      - dependency-name: "org.eclipse.jetty:jetty-maven-plugin"
        versions:
          - ">= 10.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.apache.myfaces.core:myfaces-api"
        versions:
          - ">= 3.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.apache.myfaces.core:myfaces-impl"
        versions:
          - ">= 3.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.glassfish:jakarta.faces"
        versions:
          - ">= 3.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "jakarta.inject:jakarta.inject-api"
        versions:
          - ">= 2.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "jakarta.enterprise:jakarta.enterprise.cdi-api"
        versions:
          - ">= 3.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "jakarta.servlet:jakarta.servlet-api"
        versions:
          - ">= 5.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "jakarta.servlet.jsp.jstl:jakarta.servlet.jsp.jstl-api"
        versions:
          - ">= 2.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "jakarta.validation:jakarta.validation-api"
        versions:
          - ">= 3.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "jakarta.el:jakarta.el-api"
        versions:
          - ">= 4.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "jakarta.annotation:jakarta.annotation-api"
        versions:
          - ">= 2.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.glassfish:jakarta.json"
        versions:
          - ">= 2.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.jboss.weld.servlet:weld-servlet-shaded"
        versions:
          - ">= 4.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.hibernate.validator:hibernate-validator"
        versions:
          - ">= 7.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.antlr:stringtemplate"
        versions:
          - ">= 4.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.apache.maven.plugins:maven-checkstyle-plugin"
        versions:
          - ">=3.1.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.apache.maven.plugins:maven-enforcer-plugin"
        versions:
          - ">= 3.0.0"
      # checkstyle 10 needs Java 11
      - dependency-name: "com.puppycrawl.tools:checkstyle"
        versions:
          - ">= 10.0"
      # todo: update quarkus
      - dependency-name: "io.quarkus:quarkus-maven-plugin"
        versions:
          - ">= 2.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.seleniumhq.selenium:selenium-java"
        versions:
          - ">= 4.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.apache.tomcat.embed:*"
        versions:
          - ">= 10.0.0"
      # SLF4j >= 2
      - dependency-name: "org.slf4j:*"
        versions:
          - ">= 2.0.0"
      # Logback >= 1.3 requires SLF4J 2.x
      - dependency-name: "ch.qos.logback:*"
        versions:
          - ">= 1.3.0"

  - package-ecosystem: "maven"
    directory: "/"
    target-branch: "tobago-4.x"
    commit-message:
      prefix: "build"
      prefix-development: "build"
      include: "scope"
    schedule:
      interval: "daily"
    ignore:
      - dependency-name: "com.sun.faces:jsf-api"
      - dependency-name: "com.sun.faces:jsf-impl"
      # Jetty >= 10 requires jdk 11
      - dependency-name: "org.eclipse.jetty:jetty-maven-plugin"
        versions:
          - ">= 10.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.apache.myfaces.core:myfaces-api"
        versions:
          - ">= 2.1.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.apache.myfaces.core:myfaces-impl"
        versions:
          - ">= 2.1.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.glassfish:jakarta.faces"
        versions:
          - ">= 3.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "jakarta.inject:jakarta.inject-api"
        versions:
          - ">= 2.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "jakarta.servlet.jsp.jstl:jakarta.servlet.jsp.jstl-api"
        versions:
          - ">= 2.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "jakarta.validation:jakarta.validation-api"
        versions:
          - ">= 3.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "jakarta.el:jakarta.el-api"
        versions:
          - ">= 4.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "jakarta.annotation:jakarta.annotation-api"
        versions:
          - ">= 2.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.glassfish:jakarta.json"
        versions:
          - ">= 2.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.jboss.weld.servlet:weld-servlet-shaded"
        versions:
          - ">= 4.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.hibernate:hibernate-validator"
        versions:
          - ">= 5.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.hibernate.validator:hibernate-validator"
        versions:
          - ">= 7.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.antlr:stringtemplate"
        versions:
          - ">= 4.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.apache.tomcat:tomcat-el-api"
        versions:
          - ">= 10.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.apache.tomcat:tomcat-jasper-el"
        versions:
          - ">= 10.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.apache.maven.plugins:maven-checkstyle-plugin"
        versions:
          - ">=3.1.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.apache.maven.plugins:maven-enforcer-plugin"
        versions:
          - ">= 3.0.0"
      # checkstyle 10 needs Java 11
      - dependency-name: "com.puppycrawl.tools:checkstyle"
        versions:
          - ">= 10.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.seleniumhq.selenium:selenium-java"
        versions:
          - ">= 4.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.wildfly.plugins:wildfly-maven-plugin"
        versions:
          - ">= 3.0.0"
      # SLF4j >= 2
      - dependency-name: "org.slf4j:*"
        versions:
          - ">= 2.0.0"
      # Logback >= 1.3 requires SLF4J 2.x
      - dependency-name: "ch.qos.logback:*"
        versions:
          - ">= 1.3.0"

  - package-ecosystem: "maven"
    directory: "/"
    target-branch: "tobago-2.x"
    commit-message:
      prefix: "build"
      prefix-development: "build"
      include: "scope"
    schedule:
      interval: "daily"
    ignore:
      - dependency-name: "org.apache.myfaces.core:myfaces-api"
        versions:
          - ">= 2.1.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.apache.myfaces.core:myfaces-impl"
        versions:
          - ">= 2.1.0"
      - dependency-name: "com.sun.faces:jsf-api"
        versions:
          - ">= 2.1.0"
      - dependency-name: "com.sun.faces:jsf-impl"
        versions:
          - ">= 2.1.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.apache.openwebbeans:openwebbeans-jsf"
        versions:
          - ">= 1.5.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.apache.openwebbeans:openwebbeans-web"
        versions:
          - ">= 1.5.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.apache.openwebbeans:openwebbeans-resources"
        versions:
          - ">= 1.5.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.apache.openwebbeans:openwebbeans-impl"
        versions:
          - ">= 1.5.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.apache.openwebbeans:openwebbeans-spi"
        versions:
          - ">= 1.5.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.apache.maven.plugins:maven-antrun-plugin"
        versions:
          - ">= 3.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.apache.openjpa:openjpa-persistence-jdbc"
        versions:
          - ">= 2.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.apache.maven.plugins:maven-javadoc-plugin"
        versions:
          - ">= 3.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.springframework:spring-orm"
        versions:
          - ">= 5.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.springframework:spring-jdbc"
        versions:
          - ">= 5.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.springframework:spring-web"
        versions:
          - ">= 5.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "javax.servlet.jsp:jsp-api"
        versions:
          - ">= 2.2"
      - dependency-name: "org.antlr:stringtemplate"
        versions:
          - ">= 3.1"
      - dependency-name: "org.eclipse.jetty:jetty-maven-plugin"
        versions:
          - ">= 10.0.0"
      - dependency-name: "org.seleniumhq.selenium:selenium-java"
        versions:
          - ">= 3.0.0"
      # checkstyle 10 needs Java 11
      - dependency-name: "com.puppycrawl.tools:checkstyle"
        versions:
          - ">= 10.0"
      # SLF4j >= 2
      - dependency-name: "org.slf4j:*"
        versions:
          - ">= 2.0.0"
      # Logback >= 1.3 requires SLF4J 2.x
      - dependency-name: "ch.qos.logback:*"
        versions:
          - ">= 1.3.0"

  - package-ecosystem: "github-actions"
    directory: "/"
    schedule:
      # Check for updates to GitHub Actions every day
      interval: "monthly"

  - package-ecosystem: "github-actions"
    directory: "/"
    target-branch: "tobago-5.x"
    schedule:
      # Check for updates to GitHub Actions every day
      interval: "monthly"

  - package-ecosystem: "github-actions"
    directory: "/"
    target-branch: "tobago-4.x"
    schedule:
      # Check for updates to GitHub Actions every day
      interval: "monthly"

  - package-ecosystem: "github-actions"
    directory: "/"
    target-branch: "tobago-2.x"
    schedule:
      # Check for updates to GitHub Actions every day
      interval: "monthly"

  - package-ecosystem: "npm"
    # Look for `package.json` and `lock` files in the `root` directory
    directory: "/tobago-theme"
    commit-message:
      prefix: "build"
      prefix-development: "build"
      include: "scope"
    # Check the npm registry for updates every day (weekdays)
    schedule:
      interval: "monthly"
  - package-ecosystem: "npm"
    directory: "/tobago-example/tobago-example-demo"
    commit-message:
      prefix: "build"
      prefix-development: "build"
      include: "scope"
    schedule:
      interval: "monthly"

  - package-ecosystem: "npm"
    # Look for `package.json` and `lock` files in the `root` directory
    directory: "/tobago-theme"
    target-branch: "tobago-5.x"
    commit-message:
      prefix: "build"
      prefix-development: "build"
      include: "scope"
    # Check the npm registry for updates every day (weekdays)
    schedule:
      interval: "monthly"
  - package-ecosystem: "npm"
    directory: "/tobago-example/tobago-example-demo"
    target-branch: "tobago-5.x"
    commit-message:
      prefix: "build"
      prefix-development: "build"
      include: "scope"
    schedule:
      interval: "monthly"
